<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>STEM on Fellowship of the Flux</title><link>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/tags/stem/</link><description>Recent content in STEM on Fellowship of the Flux</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/tags/stem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Welcome to Fellowship of the Flux</title><link>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/welcome-to-fellowship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/welcome-to-fellowship/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Fellowship of the Flux! We&amp;rsquo;re excited to share our mission of advancing the art of learning to solder through community outreach, education, and resource sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="our-story"&gt;Our Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fellowship of the Flux began in Kansas City with a simple belief: everyone should have the opportunity to learn soldering skills in a supportive, hands-on environment. What started as volunteer-run workshops at local cybersecurity conferences like BSides KC and MakerFaire KC has grown into a regional resource for STEM education.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building Modern Electronics Education Platforms</title><link>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/building-with-hugo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/building-with-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="building-modern-electronics-education-platforms"&gt;Building Modern Electronics Education Platforms&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating effective online learning experiences for hands-on skills like soldering presents unique challenges. How do you teach tactile skills through digital interfaces? How do you maintain engagement without physical presence? At Fellowship of the Flux, we&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring these questions while building our comprehensive learning platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-challenge-of-digital-hands-on-education"&gt;The Challenge of Digital Hands-On Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional electronics education relies heavily on in-person instruction, immediate feedback, and physical demonstration. Translating this to digital formats requires innovative approaches that complement rather than replace hands-on learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Impact of Hands-On Soldering Education</title><link>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/soldering-education-impact/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/soldering-education-impact/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After two years of volunteering with Fellowship of the Flux, I&amp;rsquo;ve witnessed firsthand the transformative power of hands-on soldering education. As a university professor, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many approaches to STEM education, but few create the immediate sense of accomplishment and confidence that comes from successfully completing your first solder joint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="beyond-technical-skills"&gt;Beyond Technical Skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While soldering is fundamentally a technical skill, the impact of learning it extends far beyond the ability to join electronic components. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve observed in our workshops:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>