<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Fellowship of the Flux</title><link>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Fellowship of the Flux</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BSides KC 2024: Record-Breaking Soldering Village</title><link>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/bsides-kc-2024-recap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/bsides-kc-2024-recap/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;What an incredible weekend at BSides Kansas City 2024! Our soldering village had its most successful year yet, with over 180 participants learning hands-on electronics skills alongside the cybersecurity conference programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="by-the-numbers"&gt;By the Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;180+ participants&lt;/strong&gt; across both days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;32 volunteers&lt;/strong&gt; providing instruction and support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zero safety incidents&lt;/strong&gt; thanks to our rigorous protocols&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15 new volunteers&lt;/strong&gt; recruited for future events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;95% completion rate&lt;/strong&gt; for beginner projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ages 8-72&lt;/strong&gt; - our most diverse age range yet!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-made-this-year-special"&gt;What Made This Year Special&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="expanded-workshop-options"&gt;Expanded Workshop Options&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year we offered three different tracks to accommodate various skill levels:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Welcome to Fellowship of the Flux</title><link>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/welcome-to-fellowship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/welcome-to-fellowship/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Fellowship of the Flux! We&amp;rsquo;re excited to share our mission of advancing the art of learning to solder through community outreach, education, and resource sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="our-story"&gt;Our Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fellowship of the Flux began in Kansas City with a simple belief: everyone should have the opportunity to learn soldering skills in a supportive, hands-on environment. What started as volunteer-run workshops at local cybersecurity conferences like BSides KC and MakerFaire KC has grown into a regional resource for STEM education.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building Modern Electronics Education Platforms</title><link>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/building-with-hugo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/building-with-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="building-modern-electronics-education-platforms"&gt;Building Modern Electronics Education Platforms&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating effective online learning experiences for hands-on skills like soldering presents unique challenges. How do you teach tactile skills through digital interfaces? How do you maintain engagement without physical presence? At Fellowship of the Flux, we&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring these questions while building our comprehensive learning platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-challenge-of-digital-hands-on-education"&gt;The Challenge of Digital Hands-On Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional electronics education relies heavily on in-person instruction, immediate feedback, and physical demonstration. Translating this to digital formats requires innovative approaches that complement rather than replace hands-on learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Impact of Hands-On Soldering Education</title><link>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/soldering-education-impact/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/soldering-education-impact/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After two years of volunteering with Fellowship of the Flux, I&amp;rsquo;ve witnessed firsthand the transformative power of hands-on soldering education. As a university professor, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many approaches to STEM education, but few create the immediate sense of accomplishment and confidence that comes from successfully completing your first solder joint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="beyond-technical-skills"&gt;Beyond Technical Skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While soldering is fundamentally a technical skill, the impact of learning it extends far beyond the ability to join electronic components. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve observed in our workshops:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Essential Soldering Techniques and Best Practices</title><link>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/tailwind-css-tips/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fellowshipoftheflux.com/posts/tailwind-css-tips/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="essential-soldering-techniques-and-best-practices"&gt;Essential Soldering Techniques and Best Practices&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After five years of teaching soldering workshops with Fellowship of the Flux, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen every mistake imaginable and learned what techniques consistently produce the best results. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re just starting out or looking to refine your skills, these tips will help you create reliable, professional-quality solder joints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="fundamental-principles"&gt;Fundamental Principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="heat-management"&gt;Heat Management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most critical aspect of good soldering is proper heat management. Your soldering iron should be hot enough to melt solder quickly but not so hot that it damages components or PCBs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>